本作品之片源来自互联网，仅供学习、交流之用。请自觉于下载后24小时内删除。任何组织和个人不得用于任何商业用途，否则一切后果请自行承担！如果喜欢本片，请购买正版！
-你慢点  -还是你快跟上吧
- Wait up. - Yeah, you should keep up.
我能跟上
I can keep up.
太酷了
Neato!
被封上的神秘山洞
Mysterious, boarded-up cave.
里面也许充满了失落的史前生物
It might be filled with lost prehistoric life forms.
或是中美洲的黄金
Or Mesoamerican gold.
女士优先
Ladies first.
幸好你自己还有智商  书呆子
Good thing you've got your smarts, Poindexter.
严禁进入
另一样东西在我这里呢
I've got the other thing.
叫什么来着
What is it called?
没错  叫拳头
Oh, right, punching.
酷  木刺扎手上了
Cool. Splinters.
这里好诡异
It's so creepy in here.
嗨  兄弟  别担心
Hey, don't worry, bro.
无论去哪儿  我们都会在一起
Wherever we go, we go together.
别忘了留个名字好让他们知道这地方是谁的
Don't forget to leave our names so they know who owns the place.
派恩斯  派恩斯  派恩斯  派恩斯
Pines, Pines, Pines, Pines.
斯坦利与斯坦福・派恩斯
■
本字幕由★迪幻字幕组★为您奉献
欢迎登录www.Deefun.com
■
翻译： 雨中的钢琴  战忽局副局座  Phoebe  阿拱
校订： violin1443  战忽局副局座
■
后期： 战忽局副局座  Theodore
怪诞小镇  第二季第十二集
Gravity Falls  S02E12  A Tale Of Two Stans
终于  等了这么多年
Finally, after all these long years of waiting,
你总算在我面前了
You're actually here.
兄弟
Brother!
你这是要干什么
What the heck was that for?
重启传送门简直危险至极
This was an insanely risky move, restarting the portal.
你没看见我的警告吗
Didn't you read my warnings?
管他什么警告
Warnings, schmarnings.
倒不如谢我的救命之恩
How's about maybe a thanks for saving you
因为我把你  从某种边缘科幻次元里救了出来
from what appears to be, I don't know, some kinda sci-fi sideburn dimension.
谢谢你  你真觉得我会谢谢你吗
Thank you? You really think I'm gonna thank you
想想你三十年前都干了什么
after what you did 30 years ago?
我干了什么
What I did?
好你个忘恩负义的
Why, you ungrateful...
别以为你是家里人
Don't expect me to go easy on you
我就不会下狠手
just because you're family.
嗨  我是梅宝
Hey, hi. Mabel here.
一个小问题
Quick question.
你们俩闹什么呢
What the heck is going on here?
斯坦  你没告诉我这儿还有孩子啊
Stan  you didn't tell me there were children down here.
还有某只又大又没毛的地鼠
And some sort of large, hairless gopher.
哈哈  好多人都这么说
Ha ha, I get that a lot.
他们是你的家人  书呆子
They're your family, Poindexter.
雪米的孙子孙女
Shermy's grandkids.
这是我侄孙和侄孙女
I have a niece, and a nephew?
你好  现在的孩子还说“你好”吗
Greetings. Do kids still say greetings?
我已经很久没在这个次元待过了
I haven't been in this dimension for a really long time.
哇噢  六指握手
Whoa, six-fingered handshake.
比一般的五指还郑重
It's a full finger friendlier than normal.
哈哈  我喜欢这孩子  挺奇怪的
Ha ha, I like this kid. She's weird.
我  我真不敢相信
I... I can't believe it.
你就是日志的作者
You're the author of the journals.
你读过我的日志
You've read my journals?
不仅读过
I haven't just read them.
还亲身体验过
I've lived them.
为了见你  我等了好久
I've been waiting for so long to meet you.
我不知道该说些啥  我有无数问题要问
I don't know what to say. I have so many questions.
我感觉快要吐了
I think I'm gonna throw up.
不  不  这次不是
No, no, false alarm.
忍忍就好了
Just gotta ride it out.
听着  不用急着现在就互相介绍
Listen, there'll be time for introductions later.
斯坦  你先告诉我
But first, tell me, Stan.
这里有没有遭遇过入侵
Are there any security breaches?
还有别人知道这个传送门吗
Does anyone else know about this portal?
没了  只有我们
No. Just us.
可能还有整个美国政府吧
Also, maybe the entire U.S. government.
你说什么
The what?!
散开  在找到斯坦・派恩斯和那些孩子
Fan out. We're not going anywhere
之前我们不会离开
till we find Stan Pines and those kids.
好吧  没关系
Okay. It's all right.
他们要找到这房间还得有好一会儿呢
We've got a while before they find this room.
我们只需要隐蔽好  再想出个计划来
We just need to lay low and think of a plan.
看起来我们得在这儿待上一段时间了
It looks like we're stuck down here for a while.
谁能给我讲讲这整件事情的神秘背景啊
Who wants to tell us their entire mysterious backstory?
是啊  我自己对此也有些疑问  斯坦利
Yes, I have some questions about all this myself, Stanley.
斯坦利
Stanley?
你的名字不是斯坦福么
But your name is Stanford.
等等  你用了我的名字
Wait, you took my name?
你这些年都在干嘛  你个蠢蛋
What have you been doing all these years, you knucklehead?
是啊  斯坦叔公  别再忽悠人了
Yeah, Grunkle Stan, no more lies.
你该给我们个交代
You owe us some answers.
这个传送门是怎么回事
What's the deal with this portal?
你为什么要藏着它
Why did you keep this a secret?
另外你和你兄弟之间到底怎么了
And what happened between you and your brother?
希望你说的都和我的同人小说一致  斯坦
I'm hoping all this aligns exactly with my fan-fic, Stan.
如果不是的话  我会很失望的
If not, I will be very disappointed.
好吧  好吧  好吧
Okay. Okay, okay.
我知道我有很多东西要解释
I know I have a lot of explaining to do.
一切得从很久以前说起
It all started a lifetime ago.
上世纪六十年代
<i> 1960-something.</i>
新泽西州碎玻璃滩
<i> Glass Shard Beach, New Jersey.</i>
我和爸妈一起住在铅漆区
<i> I lived with my ma and pa in the Lead Paint district</i>
祖传的典当行楼上
<i> above the family pawn shop.</i>
老爸是个严肃的人
<i> Dad was a strict man.</i>
原子时代
巨型玉米
面如铁石  而且难以取悦
<i> Tough as a cinder block, and not easily impressed.</i>
我毫不欣慰
I'm not impressed.
妈妈撒谎成性
<i>Mom was a pathological liar,</i>
她当个电话灵媒刚好合适
<i> which served her well as a phone psychic.</i>
一小时九毛九
That'll be 99 cents an hour.
滚  你才贵呢
No, you're overpriced.
没错  我预言你要把电话挂了
Yeah, I predicted you were gonna hang up.
还有我这书呆子双胞胎兄弟
<i>And then, there was my nerdy twin brother Stanford.</i>
智商爆表就算了
<i>As if his abnormally high IQ wasn't enough,</i>
他还有个天生的缺陷
<i> he also had a rare birth defect--</i>
畸形
双手皆为六指
<i> six fingers on each hand,</i>
怪不得他老是
<i> which might've explained his obsession</i>
喜欢科幻之类的神秘现象
<i> with sci-fi mystery weirdness.</i>
而我则拥有我妈所称道的“个性”
<i> As for me, I had what Mom liked to call personality.</i>
我们虽性格迥异
<i> But as different as we were,</i>
却是完美的组合
<i> we were the perfect team,</i>
斯坦福
斯坦利
我们每天在海滩游荡
<i> and every day, we'd wander the beach,</i>
寻找冒险机会
<i> looking for adventure.</i>
失事的船骸
A shipwrecked sailboat.
没准盘踞着海盗幽灵
Possibly haunted by pirate ghosts.
这是我见过最伟大的东西了
This is the greatest thing I've ever seen.
尽管我见过死老鼠漂在水桶里
And I once saw a dead rat floating in a bucket.
你别这么恶心啦
What's wrong with you?
你知道这东西缺点什么吗
Huh. You know what this thing's missing?
旗帜
Flags.
新泽西之王  新泽西之王
[both] Kings of New Jersey, kings of New Jersey,
新泽西之王
kings of New Jersey!
朕赐给你“大兵斯坦号”之名
I dub thee the<i> Stan O' War.</i>
噢  怎么回事
Ow! What the heck?
这不是那对废柴双胞胎吗
Well, well, if it ain't the loser twins.
船真棒  你们是从垃圾里翻出来的吧
Nice boat. You get it at the dump?
你懂什么  格兰派特  快滚
You would know, Crampelter. Get lost!
听着  呆子  而且给我听仔细
Listen, dorks, and listen good.
你是个六指的畸形
You're a six-fingered freak,
而你比他更蠢更爱出汗
and you're just a dumber, sweatier version of him.
你们俩就互相珍惜吧
And you're lucky you have each other,
因为没别人会和你们做朋友
because neither of you will ever make any friends.
呆子和废物
Dorks and losers.
嗨  别理那帮白痴
Hey, don't let those idiots get to you.
但我是个畸形
But I am a freak.
我就想知道这世界上有什么地方
I just wonder if there's anywhere in the world
能接受我这样的怪人
where weirdos like me fit in.
嗨  挺胸抬头  兄弟  看
Hey, chin up, buddy. Look.
总有那么一天
One of these days,
你我会起航离开这个落后的小镇
you and me are gonna sail away from this dumb town.
我们一起寻宝  泡妞
We'll hunt for treasure, get all the girls,
成为势不可挡的冒险家团队
and be an unstoppable team of adventurers.
你真这么想
You really mean it?
-击六指掌为誓  -击六指掌为誓
- High six? - High six.
那时的时光很美好
<i> Those were the good times.</i>
那些恶霸可能说对了
<i> Those bullies may have been right about us</i>
我们没交到什么朋友  可真到节骨眼上
<i> not making many friends, but when push comes to shove,</i>
你也就只需要一个挚友
<i> you only really need one.</i>
斯坦福的智力发育愈发令人欣慰
<i> Ford's brain seemed to get more impressive every year.</i>
我们精心经营的小理想也是如此
<i> So did our pet project.</i>
我确实惹了很多不必要的麻烦
<i> Sure, I got in more than my fair share of trouble,</i>
但要是全校最聪明的孩子是你兄弟
<i> but when your brother's the smartest kid in school,</i>
学习上就总能抱他的大腿
<i> you've always got a leg up on the competition.</i>
新泽西科学展
“什么，你觉得你是个聪明人？”
永动机
未来对我们来说如此美好
<i> The future was looking bright for both of us,</i>
直到有一天
<i> till one day.</i>
派恩斯兄弟请到校长办公室
<i>Pines twins to the principal's office.</i>
<i> Pines twins to the principal's office.</i>
好极了  这回又怎么了
Ah, great. What is it this time?
不是你  是他
Not you. Him.
派恩斯先生  我想和你谈谈
Now, Mr. Pines, I'd like to speak with you
如果可以  请恕我实话实说
very frankly, if I may.
我向来只会实话实说
Very frankly is the only way I speak.
你有两个儿子
You have two sons.
其中一个极具天赋
One of them is incredibly gifted.
另一个叫斯坦利  正站在房间外面
The other one is standing outside this room, and his name's Stanley.
你想说什么
What are you saying?
我是说你儿子斯坦福是个天才
I'm saying your son Stanford is a genius!
他的科学展实验可把所有老师都乐疯了
All of his teachers are going bananas over his science fair experiment.
听说过西岸理工吗
You ever heard of West Coast Tech?
全国最好的大学
Best college in the country.
他们的毕业生能把科幻小说变成科学事实
Their graduates turn science fiction into science fact.
大学招生组明天就来
The admissions team is visiting tomorrow
专门来观摩斯坦福的实验
to check out Stanford's experiment.
派恩斯先生  你的儿子以后很可能是个百万富翁
Your son may be a future millionaire, Mr. Pines.
我很欣慰
I'm impressed.
可我们那生性不羁的斯坦利呢
But what about our little free spirit Stanley?
那傻小子  看他现在的水平
That clown? At this rate,
能高中毕业就该谢天谢地了
he'll be lucky to graduate high school.
听着  码头那边有个卖盐水太妃糖的店
Look, there's a saltwater taffy store on the dock,
他们总得雇人去把粘在底下的贝壳刮掉
and somebody's gotta get paid to scrape the barnacles off of it.
斯坦福将要远走高飞
Stanford's going places,
但往好的方向看
but hey, look on the bright side.
你们至少还有一个儿子永远留在新泽西嘛
At least you'll have one son here in New Jersey forever.
你总不会被他们忽悠得
Joke's on them if they think
屁颠屁颠跑到美国另一头上大学吧
you wanna go to some stuffy college on the other side of the country.
一旦大兵斯坦号建成
Once we get the Stan O' War complete,
不论是海滩还是美女
it's gonna be beaches, babes,
还有国际大寻宝都唾手可得了
and international treasure hunting for us.
听着  斯坦  我可不能错过这个机会
Look, Stan, I can't pass up a chance like this.
这所大学里有最前沿的项目
This school has cutting-edge programs
还有多维范式理论的研究呢
and multi-dimensional paradigm theory.
我是个书呆子机器人
I am a nerd robot.
你就是这样的  你说话就像这样
That's you. That's what you sound like.
好吧
Well,
要是招生组明天对我的实验不满意
if the college board isn't impressed with my experiment tomorrow,
那我就跟你一块儿寻宝去
then okay, I'll do the treasure hunting thing.
如果他们很满意呢
And if they are?
那就希望你多去西海岸
Well, then I guess you better come visit me
看看我咯
on the other side of the country.
没了阿福  我只不过是活力二人组的一半
Without Ford, I was just half of a dynamic duo.
没了他  我什么都不是
I couldn't make it out there without him.
现在可好
And now,
这所破大学要把我兄弟永远带走了
thanks to that dumb college, I was gonna lose my brother forever.
全都是你的错  破烂机器
This is all your fault, you dumb machine!
噢  不  不  不  我到底干了什么
Oh, no. No, no, no. What did I do?
这样就好了
There. All right.
看起来跟新的一样  应该吧
Good as new. Probably.
好了  孩子  来展示一下你的能耐
All right, kid, show us what you got.
呃  好  请允许我告诉你
Okay. Well, what would you say
科学发展的未来
if I told you the future of technology
就在白布后面
was beneath this sheet?
请允许我告诉你  我们白跑了
I'd say we wasted a car trip.
什么
What?
昨天还好好的呢
But it was stable yesterday.
一定是保险丝熔了或者怎么的
A fuse must've blown or something.
孩子  永动机的工作只有一个
Kid, a perpetual motion machine has one job--
永远动着
to not stop.
看来西岸理工你是去不成了
I don't think you're West Coast Tech material.
不  别走啊
No, wait. Don't go!
我这么努力
I worked so hard.
一哒哒哒  二哒哒
One paddle paddle paddle, two paddle paddle.
这个叫杰奎的长得还挺火辣
Man, that Jackie O. What a fox.
喂  六指  他们咋说的
Hey, what's the word, sixer?
你给我解释一下
Can you explain
为什么这个袋子会出现在我坏掉的仪器边上
what this was doing next to my broken project?
呃  我可能不小心在周围
Okay. I might've accidentally been...
转悠
horsing around.
这可不是不小心  斯坦  就是你干的
This was no accident, Stan. You did this.
你来搞破坏是因为
You did this because
你不能接受我独自一人去上大学
you couldn't handle me going to college on my own.
听着  我不是故意的
Look, it was a mistake.
不过你仔细想想
Although, if you think about it,
还是有好的一方面的
maybe there's a silver lining.
对吧  一起去寻宝呗
Huh? Treasure hunting?
你是在逗我呢吧
Are you kidding me?
我为什么要跟你这么一个
Why would I wanna do anything with the person
毁了我整个人生的人合作
who sabotaged my entire future?
你这败家子干了什么
You did what, you knucklehead?
斯坦利  到底发生了什么
Stanley, what's going on in here?
等等  听我解释  我不是故意的
Wait, no. I can explain. It was a mistake.
你个愚笨的废物
You ignoramus.
本来就指望你兄弟让全家过上好日子
Your brother was gonna be our ticket outta this dump.
你就只会撒谎欺骗
All you ever do is lie and cheat,
坐你兄弟的顺风车
and ride on your brother's coattails.
现在可好  全家未来的几百万
Well, this time, you cost our family
就被你败光了
potential millions.
除非你能赚来一大笔钱
And until you make us a fortune,
不然就永远离开这个家吧
you're not welcome in this household.
什么  斯坦福  别让他这么丧失理智
What?! Stanford, tell him he's being crazy.
斯坦福  别让我一个巴掌拍不响啊
Stanford? Don't leave me hanging.
击个六指掌吗
High six?
好  我一个人照样能行
Fine! I can make it on my own.
我不需要你们  我谁都不需要
I don't need you, I don't need anyone.
我会变成百万富翁  而你们就
I'll make millions, and you'll rue the day
为今天的举动后悔吧
you turned your back on me.
就因为这一个白痴错误  我没了兄弟
Thanks to one dumb mistake, I had no brother,
没了家  什么都没有
no home, no nothing.
但是我有一个万全之策
But I had a plan to fix everything.
这故事真悲伤
This story's so sad.
我知道你们两个破碎的小茶壶需要什么
I know what you two little broken teacups need.
拥抱一个
To hug it out.
一抱泯恩仇
Hug it out.
抱抱火车进站咯
Hug train comin' in the station.
抱你命2000
Hugapalooza 2000!
孩子  能别这样吗
Kid, will you knock that off?
听我把我的人生故事讲完
I'm trying to tell my life story here.
我决心不再回到家中
I had decided I wasn't gonna show my face at home
除非我自己赚到了足够的钱
till I proved I could make something of myself.
悲哀的是  寻宝生意
Unfortunately, the treasure hunting business
进展缓慢
was slow going.
很明显  黄金确实是贵金属
Apparently, gold is some kind of rare metal.
幸运的是  我在别的行业里捞到了第一桶金
Luckily, I struck another kind of gold.
旅行销售员
自己当老板
销售业
In sales.
大家好啊  我是斯坦・派恩斯
Hi there. I'm Stan Pines
来自斯坦科集团公司
of Stanco Enterprises.
生活中的这种事是否让您心烦意乱
Are you sick of this always happening to you?
那么“未来软布”就是您最好的选择
Then you need the chamois of the future.
这种材料和宇航员在月球上
Made with the same material astronauts use
用来清理酸梅酱渍的材料一模一样
to clean up cranberry stains on the moon.
这里是赝品大卖场
That's the Sham Total.
为您奉献最佳赝品
It's a total sham.
我的品牌火起来了  是件好事
I had made my mark, all right.
（注：“火起来”又有“掉色”的意思）
不过软布也掉色了
Unfortunately, so did the chamois.
我用来染软布的廉价颜料
Apparently, the cheap dye I used to color them
只会给清理衣服帮倒忙
only made stains worse.
顾客们对这个不是太满意
Customers weren't crazy about that.
还好我走运  他们手上拿的
Luckily, they were chasing me
是斯坦科牌的耙子
with Stanco-brand pitchforks.
傻蛋
Suckers!
我彻底被逐出了新泽西州
I was officially banned from New Jersey.
您正在离开新泽西州
不过换了个名字
But with a quick name change,
斯蒂夫・派宁顿准备在宾夕法尼亚大干一场了
Steve Pinington was ready to take on Pennsylvania.
大家好  我是斯蒂夫・派宁顿
Hi. I'm Steve Pinington.
创可贴是不是很难撕下来呢
Are you sick of bandages that are hard to remove?
你需要的就是快撕贴
Then what you need is the Rip Off.
（注：“快撕”又有“坑人货”的意思）
快撕贴保准不让你发疹
The Rip Off won't give you rashes.
重复一遍  保准不让你发疹
I repeat, it won't give you rashes.
保准不让你发疹
发疹了别找我
It gave you rashes.
欢迎您再次光临宾夕法尼亚州
我走遍了整个国家
I traveled the whole country,
甚至出了几次国
sometimes outside of it,
总是先法律一步
always one step ahead of the law,
寻找人生的转机
looking for something that would be my big break.
所以这堆假身份就是这么来的
Whoa. So that explains all the fake ID's.
等等  那你呢
But wait, what about you?
你最后上了梦想中的大学吗
Did you end up going to your dream school?
没有
Not exactly.
我知道各位都不会首选备胎多大学
All right, I know Backupsmore wasn't anyone's first choice,
我们虽然没啥名气
but what we lack in prestige
但是我们的宿舍保准虫子最少
we make up for in mostly bug-free dorms.
各位的家人一定很骄傲
I'm sure your families are proud.
多多少少吧
More or less.
在这种地方  我只能加倍努力
In a place like that, I had to work twice as hard.
幸好我很擅长这个
Luckily, that's what I do best.
从入学开始到拿博士学位
I went from undergrad to PhD
我比别人提前了三年
three years ahead of schedule,
写了一份全国知名的毕业论文
wrote a thesis that was nationally ranked,
又因为科学研究
and was awarded an enormous grant
拿到了一大笔奖金
for my own scientific research.
但我到底要研究什么呢
But what to study?
我这辈子  别人一直都笑话
My whole life, I'd been teased
我的六个指头
for my six fingers.
而这让我不禁深入思考起反常现象
But that got me thinking about anomalies.
反常现象
奇怪的  不正常的
Things that were odd, unusual,
统计学上概率近乎于零的
statistically improbable.
根据我的调查
And according to my investigations,
有一个地方发生这类事件的比例
there was one place with a higher concentration
比其他任何地方都大
of these things than anywhere else.
俄勒冈州路匪县的一个小木材出口镇
A small lumber town in Roadkill County, Oregon.
反常现象发生地
重力泉
Gravity Falls.
不许我入境的州
与此同时  你们叔公斯坦过得可好了
Meanwhile, your old Uncle Stan was doing great.
我想出了一个
I'd come up with
复杂精致的商业计划
a sophisticated new business strategy.
拜托  猫头鹰  猫头鹰
Come on. Owl, owl...
拿着蛋饼的橄榄球员
Football player with an omelet?!
我体型健康  生活独立
I was in great shape, living on my own,
最棒的是  我不需要任何人的帮助
and the best part was, I didn't need help from nobody.
你好  我是斯坦福・派恩斯
Hello. This is Stanford Pines.
与此同时  我也在独自打拼
I was heading out on my own, as well.
我开始着手利用我的补助金
I set to work using my grant money
来调查这座小镇的奇怪现象
to investigate the strange properties of this town.
但我会在这里找到什么呢
But what would I find here?
太好啦  我立马展开调查
Bingo. I began to investigate at once.
我知道我要把发现的成果记下来
I knew I'd have to record my findings.
所以我开始写日志
I began to keep a journal.
日志
The journals!
抱歉  抱歉
Sorry, sorry.
我听到日志就难以按捺激动之情
Got excited there about the journals.
请继续说
Keep talking.
我开始写日志
I began to keep a journal.
就当我没听见吧
I'm going to ignore that.
这里到处充满奇异事物
There were anomalies everywhere.
我找得越多  看到的就越多
And the more I looked, the more I saw.
悬浮崖
非自然形成
太迷人了
Fascinating.
你刚刚说你叫什么名字
What did you say your name was?
老史麦布莱克
Shmebulock... Senior.
我终于找到像家一般的地方
It was finally a place where I felt at home,
但有件事令我很困扰
but something nagged at me.
这些东西从哪来的
Where did it all come from?
在我看来
It seemed to me
答案一定在我们的世界之外
the answer must lie outside of our world,
是从一个充满怪诞事物的次元泄露的
a dimension of weirdness leaking into ours.
我意识到要想探究重力泉的唯一办法
I realized the only way to understand Gravity Falls
就是建一道传送门  一个入口
would be to build a gateway, a portal
连接到怪诞事物的源头
to the source of its weirdness.
但靠我自己是不够的
But I couldn't make it alone.
我决定联系我以前的大学同学
I decided to call up my old college buddy,
费多福・麦戈科特
Fiddleford McGucket,
一位年轻有为的机械师
a young but brilliant mechanic
他把他的才华浪费在
who was wasting his talent
帕洛阿尔托的某座车库里
trying to make personal computers
试图生产个人电脑
in some garage in Palo Alto.
费多福电脑公司  你好
Hello. Fiddleford Computermajigs.
你说你在尝试建造
You say you're trying to build
一个连接宇宙的多维元漩涡
a trans-universal poly-dimensional meta vortex?
这个从数学角度看是可行的呀
Well, that's mathematically feasible,
我猜是吧
I reckon.
无数个漫漫长夜在完善机器中度过
Many long nights were spent perfecting the machine.
找出这座小镇怪诞现象根源的答案
It would be the crowning achievement of my studies,
将会是我学术生涯中无上的成就
an answer to the source of this town's anomalies.
快走  快走  快走
Get out, get out, get out!
测试机器的日子终于到了
The time had come to test it.
准备好了吗  下一步
Ready? And...
什么
What?
我抓住你了  伙计
I got you, buddy.
那边是什么  机器起作用了吗
What is it? Is it working?
你看到了什么
What did you see?
费多福
Fiddleford?
当重力泉和地面变成天空时
When Gravity Falls and earth becomes sky,
敬畏独眼怪兽吧
fear the beast with just one eye.
费多福  你冷静点
Fiddleford, get a hold of yourself.
我完全听不懂你说什么
You're not making any sense.
这台机器很危险
This machine is dangerous.
你会因此而毁掉世界的
You'll bring about the end of the world with this.
在机器毁灭全人类之前销毁它
Destroy it before it destroys us all!
这怎么能行  这是我的毕生心血
I can't destroy this. It's my life's work.
恐怕我们已将巨大的危险释放到地球上
I fear we've unleashed a great danger on the world.
我希望能把这忘掉  我退出
One I'd just as soon forget. I quit.
好啊  我会自己完成它
Fine. I'll do it without you.
我不需要你  也不需要任何人
I don't need you, I don't need anyone.
什么  谁在说话
What? Who said that?
我当时脑袋一团糟
I was in over my head,
害怕自己正在失去理智
and feared I was losing my sanity.
我需要某个我能信赖的人来帮助我
I needed help. Someone I could trust.
斯坦科公司值得信赖
再多给我几天时间  里科
Just give me a few more days, Rico.
我发誓会把钱还到你的打手那儿
I'll pay your goons back, I swear.
请过来
阿福
斯坦福・派恩斯
俄勒冈州重力泉
地鼠路618号
斯坦利・派恩斯
新墨西哥州
死胡同公寓005号
严禁       闯入
你已经超过十年没见你的兄弟了
You haven't seen your brother in over ten years.
没关系的  他是家人  他不咬人的
It's okay. He's family. He won't bite.
是谁  你是来偷我的眼睛吗
Who is it? Have you come to steal my eyes?
你这欢迎还真够热烈啊
Well, I can always count on you for a warm welcome.
斯坦利  有没有人跟踪你  任何人
Stanley, did anyone follow you, anyone at all?
你也好啊  伙伴
Hello to you, too, pal.
嘿  这是干什么
Hey, what is this?
抱歉  我只是要确保你不是
Sorry. I just had to make sure you weren't...
没事了
uh, it's nothing.
进来吧  进来吧
Come in, come in.
你还不解释解释怎么回事
Look, are you gonna explain what's going on here?
你表现得跟老妈喝完十杯咖啡一样
You're acting like Mom after her tenth cup of coffee.
听着  没时间了
Listen, there isn't much time.
我犯了个大错误
I've made huge mistakes,
我不知道我还能相信谁
and I don't know who I can trust anymore.
嘿  放轻松  我们好好谈一谈  好吗
Hey, easy there. Let's talk this through, okay?
我要给你看样东西
I have something to show you.
一样你不会相信的东西
Something you won't believe.
我可是周游过世界的人
Look, I've been around the world, okay?
无论是什么  我都会懂的
Whatever it is, I'll understand.
我完全不懂这是什么东西
There is nothing about this I understand.
这是个连接宇宙的大门
It's a trans-universal gateway,
是一个穿过我们维度中某个脆弱点的孔洞
a punched hole through a weak spot in our dimension.
我制造了它来解封宇宙的神秘事物
I created it to unlock the mysteries of the universe.
但用它也可以轻易地造成巨大破坏
But it could just as easily be harnessed for terrible destruction.
这就是我关闭机器并藏起日志的原因
That's why I shut it down and hid my journals
因为日志里解释了如何操作机器
which explain how to operate it.
现在只剩一本日志了
There's only one journal left.
你是我唯一能放心交付日志的人
You are the only person I can trust to take it.
我要问你个问题
I have something to ask of you.
还记得我们要划船环游世界的计划吗
Remember our plans to sail around the world on a boat?
带上这本书  乘船离开
Take this book, get on a boat,
走得越远越好
and sail as far away as you can.
去到天涯海角
To the edge of the earth.
把它埋在没人能找到的地方
Bury it where no one can find it.
就这样吗
That's it?
十年之后你终于想起要见我
You finally wanna see me after ten years,
就是为了告诉我离你越远越好
and it's to tell me to get as far away from you as possible?
斯坦利  你不明白我面临的处境
Stanley, you don't understand what I'm up against.
我所经历的一切
What I've been through.
不  是你不明白我经历了什么
No, no, you don't understand what I've been through.
我曾经在三个国家锒铛入狱
I've been to prison in three different countries.
有一次我不得不撬开后备箱逃走
I once had to chew my way out of the trunk of a car.
你以为你有麻烦了
You think you've got problems?
我的麻烦多到数不清  斯坦福
I've got a mullet, Stanford.
与此同时  你又在哪里呢
Meanwhile, where have you been?
你在树林中漂亮的小屋里快活
Living it up in your fancy house in the woods,
自私地屯着你大学的学费
selfishly hoarding your college money,
因为你只在乎你自己
because you only care about yourself.
我自私吗  我自私吗
I'm selfish? I'm selfish?
斯坦利  你怎么能这么说
Stanley, how can you say that
是你让我梦想中的大学化作泡影
after costing me my dream school?
我在给你机会  让你做一件你生命中最有价值的事情
I'm giving you a chance to do the first worthwhile thing in your life,
可你连听都不听
and you won't even listen.
那你听我说
Well, listen to this.
你想让我丢掉这本书
You want me to get rid of this book?
好啊  我现在就让它彻底不见
Fine, I'll get rid of it right now.
不  你不明白
No! You don't understand.
你说你想让我保管它
You said you wanted me to have it,
那我爱把它怎样都不关你的事
so I'll do what I want with it.
我的研究成果啊
My research!
斯坦利  还给我
Stanley, give it back.
你想拿回它  那你就要更努力点
You want it back, you're gonna have to try harder than that.
你抛弃了我  你个混蛋
You left me behind, you jerk.
我们本可以永远在一起的
It was supposed to be us forever.
-你毁掉我的生活  -是你毁掉自己的生活
- You ruined my life.  - You ruined your own life.
斯坦利  天啊  我很抱歉
Stanley. Oh, my gosh, I'm so sorry.
你还好吗
Are you all right?
你就这样还有脸和我当亲兄弟
Some brother you turned out to be.
你在乎你那愚蠢的神秘事件  远多于你的家庭
You care more about your dumb mysteries than your family.
那你就拿着去吧
Then you can have 'em.
噢  噢  嘿  怎么回事
Whoa, whoa, hey. What's going on?
-嘿  斯坦福  -斯坦利  救我
- Hey, Stanford... - Stanley, help me!
-哦不  我该做什么  -斯坦利
- Oh no! What do I do? - Stanley!
斯坦利  做点什么
Stanley, do something!
斯坦福
Stanford?
斯坦福  回来  我不是故意的
Stanford, come back. I didn't mean it.
他才回到我的身边
I just got him back.
我不能再失去他了
I can't lose him again.
快点
Come on!
斯坦福
Stanford!
我失去了他
I'd lost him.
我无从得知他在某个遥远的星系里
I didn't know if he was dead or alive
2号日志中继续
是死是活
in some distant galaxy,
2号日志中继续
但我知道日志里面一定会有某种办法
but I knew his journal must have the answer
可以把他带回来
to getting him back... somehow.
那晚我一夜无眠
I didn't get much sleep that night.
自从那晚以后都是如此
Or the night after that.
我试了好几周想重启那台破机器
<i> I tried for weeks to turn that dumb machine back on.</i>
可没有另外两本日志
<i> But without</i> <i> the other two journals,</i>
一切都是徒劳
<i> it was hopeless.</i>
最后我吃光了食物
<i> Finally, I ran out of food.</i>
没办法只好去了镇上
<i> I had no choice but to go into town.</i>
只要面包吗  陌生人
Just the bread then, stranger?
一共九毛九
That'll be 99 cents.
那可不是什么陌生人
That's no stranger.
他一定是住在树林里的
That must be the mysterious science guy
那个神秘科学家
that lives in the woods.
不不  你们认错人了
No, no, you got the wrong guy.
我听过许多关于那栋老房子的奇怪传闻
I've heard strange stories about that old shack.
是啊  诡异的灯光和可怕的实验
Yeah, mysterious lights and spooky experiments.
天哪  为了看看里面是啥
Gosh, I'd pay anything
要我给多少钱我都给
to see what kind of shenanigans you get up to in there.
我也是  你对外开放参观吗
Me, too. Do you ever give tours?
没有  我
No, really, I...
是啊  我那儿开放参观
Yes, I do give tours.
十  不不  每人十五块钱
Ten... no, no, 15 bucks a person.
那你叫什么名字
So what did you say your name was,
神秘的先生
you man of mystery?
噢  斯坦  福
Oh, Stan... ford.
斯坦福・派恩斯
Stanford Pines.
大家都进来吧
Step right up, folks,
欢迎来到魔法世界或管它什么世界
to a world of enchantment or whatever.
给你看看这个古怪科学盒
Behold the nerdy science box.
啊我的眼睛
Ah! My eye!
我向你保证  你的眼睛一会儿就好了
Uh, I can assure you, that is in no way permanent.
我花了十五块钱就为了看这个
I paid $15 for this?
你们比上一个观光团幸运多了
Uh, you're lucky you weren't part of the last tour group.
他们可没能活着参观完哦
They never made it out alive.
是吧
Right?
真搞笑
Funny.
所以我有了个好主意
<i> So I came up with a plan.</i>
我不能离开我兄弟的房子
<i> I couldn't leave my brother's house</i>
往前走
除非我知道如何救他回来
<i> until I figured out how to save him.</i>
概不退款
但是我需要还他的贷款
<i> But I needed to pay his mortgage somehow.</i>
我人生中第一次
<i>For once in my life,</i>
人们真的会来买我卖的东西
<i> people were actually buying what I was selling.</i>
就这样  谋杀小屋诞生了
<i> And so, the Murder Hut was born.</i>
后来改名为神秘小屋
<i> Later renamed the Mystery Shack.</i>
我终于找到了自己擅长的事
<i> Finally, I'd found something I was good at.</i>
这一次  我骗人的经验有了用武之地
<i> For once, being a liar and a cheat paid off.</i>
过去的我已经死了
<i> The old me was dead.</i>
我还伪造了一场车祸来掩盖真相
<i> And I faked a car crash to prove it.</i>
白天  我是斯坦福・派恩斯  神秘先生
<i>By day, I was Stanford Pines, Mr. Mystery.</i>
但黑夜降临  我就会来到地下室
<i> But by night, I was</i> <i> down in the basement,</i>
想方设法找回真正的斯坦福
<i> trying to bring the real Stanford back.</i>
我不能冒险让其他人知道真相
<i> I couldn't risk anyone learning the truth</i>
那样他们会阻拦我完成使命
<i> and sabotaging my mission.</i>
所以我对所有人都撒了谎
So I lied to everyone.
小镇  我的家人  你们的父母
The town, my family, your parents.
甚至你们俩
Even you kids.
所以一直以来  你只是在设法救你的兄弟
So all this time, you were just trying to save your brother.
斯坦叔公  非常抱歉我没有信任你
Grunkle Stan, I'm so sorry I didn't believe you.
没关系  孩子
That's okay, kid.
大概就连我自己也不会信任我吧
I probably wouldn't have believed me either.
我听到了说话声  从楼下传来的
I heard talking. It was coming from downstairs.
太迟了  特工们要找到我们了
No, it's too late. The agents are coming for us.
我们该怎么办
What'll we do?
天哪  我简直被你的戏剧性故事迷住了
Oh, man, I was so spellbound by your dramatic tale,
都忘记了那些家伙们
I forgot all about those dudes.
等等  我差点忘了  就是它了
Wait. Forget. That's it.
我想也许我们能用它打败那些特工们
I think I know a way we might be able to defeat those agents.
没错
Of course.
我不知道你怎么得到这些东西的
I don't know how you got a hold of one of these,
不过这个真是非常合适
but this is perfect.
我只要把信号放大到无线电耳机的频率上就行
I can just amplify the signal to a radio headset frequency.
确定目标  现在大家快捂住耳朵
There. Now everyone, plug your ears!
现在趴下
Get down now!
长官  自动售货机后面
Sir, looks like there's a hidden door
貌似有一个暗门
behind the vending machines.
好极了  给我在一号线连华盛顿
Excellent. Get me Washington on line one.
为了这次重大场合  我一直在练习怎样发出兴奋的声音
I've been practicing making sounds of excitement for this very occasion.
嘿  你听见了吗
Hey, do you hear that?
天哪  我这是在哪儿
What? Where am I?
我怎么站在一个滑稽可笑的小房子外面
Why am I standing in some sort of goofy, fun knick-knack house?
先生们  戒备解除
Stand down, gentlemen.
我是华盛顿特使  前来传达最新消息
I've been sent with the latest intel from Washington.
根据这份非常真实的报告
According to this very real report,
出现在重力泉的力量
the power surges in Gravity Falls
其实是由一场未被报告的
were actually due to radiation
流星雨的辐射导致
from an unreported meteor shower.
这次错误行动让你们部门颜面扫地
A total embarrassment for your whole department.
幸运的是  我到这里来帮你们收拾烂摊子
Luckily, I'm here to take this mess off your hands.
我需要你们上交全部的软盘
I'll need all of your floppy disks,
还是叫磁带盘来着
and, uh, eight tracks. Right?
有关此案的全部情报都存在这个U盘里
Uh, everything about this case is contained on this drive.
那你们还在等什么  吻别礼吗
Well, what are you waiting for? A kiss on the cheek?
趁我还没军法审判你们前  赶紧离开这儿
Get outta here before I have your butts court-martialed.
遵命  长官  抱歉  长官
Uh, yes, sir. Apologies, sir.
错误警报  所有人归队
False alarm, everyone.
斯坦福叔公  真是太了不起啦
Great-uncle Stanford, that was amazing.
也别那么疯狂  这招很平常嘛
Let's not go crazy. It was serviceable.
孩子们  谢谢
Ha ha, thank you, kids.
不过还是叫我阿福吧
But please, call me Ford.
好的  谢谢您  阿福叔公
Sure. Thanks, great-uncle Ford.
那个  我能不能向您请教
So, uh, would you mind if I asked you
小几百万个有关重力泉的问题
a couple million questions about Gravity Falls?
呃我
Um, well, I, uh...
好了孩子们  日子还长着呢
All right, kids, it's been a long day.
我们兄弟俩之间有很多要谈的
Me and my brother have a lot to talk about.
-你们为什么不先去睡觉呢  -可他是作者呀
- Why don't you hit the hay, huh? - But it's the author.
我等了好久好久就是想问问题
I've been waiting so long to ask questions about--
我说了  去睡觉
I said, hit the hay!
我会圆润地离开的
I'll just let myself out.
温蒂  我有超精彩的故事要告诉你
Wendy, I've got something amazing to tell you.
接下来十四小时你就不要干别的了
Clear the next 14 hours.
看看我们
Look at us.
什么时候就变成老头子了
When did we become old men?
你和爸很像
You look like Dad.
别这么说
Don't say that.
斯坦利  你看这样行吗
Okay, Stanley, here's the deal.
这个夏天你可以留在这儿看着孩子们
You can stay here for the summer to watch the kids.
而我会待在地下室里
I'll stay down in the basement
努力控制可能存余的危险
and try to contain any remaining damage.
夏天结束后
When the summer's over,
你把房子还给我
you give me my house back,
名字也还给我
you give me my name back,
然后永远关掉这个破烂神秘小屋
and this Mystery Shack junk is over forever.
明白了吗
You got it?
你真的不打算感谢我  是吧
You really aren't gonna thank me, are you?
好吧  但我也有一个条件
Fine. On one condition.
离孩子们远点
You stay away from the kids.
我不想让他们陷入危险
I don't want them in danger.
因为对我来说
'Cause as far as I'm concerned,
他们是我仅剩的家人了
they're the only family I have left.
你听见他们说什么了吗
Did you hear what they said?
我听见阿福叔公说
I think Uncle Ford said
他们要给咱们买冰激凌小狗
they're gonna buy us puppies made of ice cream.
可能是我一厢情愿吧
Might be wishful thinking, though.
我不知道现在的情况是好是坏
I don't know if this is good or bad.
我是很想见作者  可
I wanted to meet the author, but...
是啊  我也怀念以前的生活
Yeah. I liked the way things were here before.
只有我们和斯坦叔公
Just us and Stan,
偶尔还有小矮人
and the occasional goblin monster.
我相信他们会解决好一切的
I'm sure they'll work things out.
迪普  你觉不觉得我们长大以后
Dipper, you don't think we'll turn out
也会变得像斯坦和阿福一样呢
like Stan and Ford, do you?
什么意思
What do you mean?
我是说  他们曾经是最好的朋友
I mean, they used to be best friends,
可后来  他们都变成了傻瓜
but then, they got all stupid.
你能向我保证你不会也犯傻吗
Can you promise me you won't get stupid?
反正肯定没你傻  傻瓜
Not stupider than you, dum-dum.
晚安  傻瓜
Good night, stupid.
好吧好吧  结果另外一个斯坦
<i>Okay okay, so it turns out the second Stan,</i>
也就是我们认识的斯坦
<i> the Stan that we know,</i>
其实是斯坦利
<i>was actually Stanley,</i>
而第一个斯坦是斯坦福
<i> but the first Stan was Stanford,</i>
可直到斯坦福
<i> but we didn't know </i>
从他自己建的传送门里出来时
<i> until Stanford came out of the portal,</i>
我们才搞清楚了怎么回事
<i> which was built</i> <i> by Stanford,</i>
后来斯坦利假装是斯坦福
<i> but then Stanley pretending to be Stanford,</i>
他建了传送门  因为他是斯坦
<i> he did the portal cause he's Stan,</i>
然而他并不是斯坦
<i> but he's not Stan.</i>
苏斯  现在已经凌晨三点了
Soos, it's 3:00 in the morning.
好的  我知道了
<i> Okay, okay, I understand.</i>
总之  第二幕  斯坦开始
<i> Anyway, act two,</i> <i> Stan started...</i>